<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Hadi Sinaee</title><link>https://hadisinaee.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Hadi Sinaee</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:34:53 +0430</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hadisinaee.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction To Cloud and Distributed Systems - Part One</title><link>https://hadisinaee.github.io/posts/distributed-systems-part-one/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:34:53 +0430</pubDate><guid>https://hadisinaee.github.io/posts/distributed-systems-part-one/</guid><description>TLDR This post is the first part of a series of posts about cloud and distributed systems. In this part, I try to introduce some of the fundamental concepts of distributed systems along with their properties — moreover, a gentle introduction to MapReduce, and Apache YARN architecture. I will discuss the definition of distributed systems. I am then introducing some of the essential features of it. After that, MapReduce is presented as a paradigm for writing a distributed application with the classic wordcount example.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up Ubuntu Server 18.04 on Virtualbox 6</title><link>https://hadisinaee.github.io/posts/setting-up-ubuntu-server-18.04-on-virtualbox-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 23:07:48 +0430</pubDate><guid>https://hadisinaee.github.io/posts/setting-up-ubuntu-server-18.04-on-virtualbox-6/</guid><description>TLDR; In this post, I am going to set up a cluster of ubuntu servers using Virtualbox 6 on a Mac OS. I will assign a static IP address to each VM using netplan and change its hostname permanently. Moreover, I will set up a NAT and Host-Only networks for having internet access and ssh accessibility from the host.
Requirements Host-Only Networks NAT Networks Change Your Host Name Create Another Node Summary Requirements I suppose that you have installed the Virtualbox 6.</description></item></channel></rss>